JUAN GALLARDO

🗣 Edmonton, Alberta, Canada 💌 juan.gallardo.ab@gmail.com 🛘 (780) 862-9404 🛅 https://ca.linkedin.com/in/jgallardo-dev 📥 https://github.com/Juan-G-04

SUMMARY

Full-stack web developer currently in an ongoing diploma course with Innotech College. A self taught and self starter with a passion for programming and a desire to expand knowledge and skill in the workspace. Has experience with real clients and projects.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Developer Diploma Ongoing

Innotech College Alberta

• Started September 2020 and concluding in March 2021.

PROJECTS

Ascended Guild (WoW guild website)

2020

Freelance for client

- Built custom website as first point of contact for prospective players and facilitates ease of application.
- Presents information in a clear, attractive, and effective manner.
- The client can easily update the site with no programming knowledge necessary.
- Database made using mySQL through entity framework core. ASP.net core and CSS for front end.

Renova Contracting

2020

Freelance for client

- First point of contact for prospective clients with a desire for custom renovations who need a quote.
- Provides an intuitive and attractive marquee gallery that promotes the contractors prowess and custom services offered.
- Facilitates easy communication with contractor for prospective clients.

SKILLS

Design: Knowledge and hands-on experience building websites from concept to completion using best software development practices (ex. standard HTML, CSS), which includes the ability to gather client requirements, integrate data (i.e. from back-end databases), and leverage network diagnostics / analytics tools (ex. Search Engine Optimization).

Coding, Testing and Problem-Solving: Demonstrated experience writing well designed, testable, efficient code, which includes the creative skill to perform problem diagnosis as well as maintain and / or scale-up the integrity and security of the site and related web applications.

Software Knowledge and Skills: Theoretical knowledge and some experience using the following web languages, development and maintenance software and systems: HTML5, CSS3, MySQL, JavaScript, jQuery, SSH, Git, and all major browsers and OS's.

Project Management: Knowledge and skill supporting all stages (ex. planning, scheduling) of the project management process with knowledge of both the Waterfall and Scrum methodologies. Proven success finishing assigned projects on time, within budget and according to approved KPI's.

Client Relations: Bilingual (English & Spanish) speaker with an outstanding ability to positively communicate and work with a variety of different stakeholders (ex. managers, clients), which includes a solid reputation for building collaborative work relationships at all levels in an organization.

Javascript: Knowledge of modern features such as arrow functions, promises, and destructuring,

HTML: Knowledge of accessibility features and topics, semantic HTML.

CSS: Native features, modularity, preprocessors, and frameworks.

C#: Used in professional projects, use of ASP.NET Core MVC Framework, and database access

Bash Scripting: Creating dynamic scripts take command line input and create complex file structure and content.

Github: Extensive and regular use of both Git and Github

Linux based OS: Daily driver, most tasks through CLI, file permissions and manipulation through CLI.

EXPERIENCE

Lead Administrator

July 2020 - Current

• Valor Distributions | Edmonton, AB

- Maintaining a high trust position fulfilling online orders, maintaining counts, promoting and organizing orders for physical picker efficiency.
- Time and personnel management in the workplace, delegation of tasks and order fulfillments, and streamlining workflows daily.
- Implementing cost effective practices in scheduling and work scope leading to less work-hours and more productivity.
- Interacting with clients as a liaison, fielding calls, questions, and in-person pickups.

Surveyor Assistant

Jan 2017 - Dec 2019

• Universal Geomatics Solutions Corp. | Edmonton, AB

- Working outside, analyzing and interpreting data, long periods of standing, climbing, and hiking.
- Assisting and supporting surveyors in field surveys and construction layout.
- Assisting surveyors in drafting survey notes and detailed drawings.
- Conducting on-field survey and record measurements using a variety of information technologies.

Volunteer Research Assistant

Sept 2017 - Jan 2018

• University of Alberta Chemistry Department with the Harynuck Research Group

- | Edmonton, AB
- Procuring, cataloguing, and pyrolyzing small samples of household material for chemical research.
- Utilized with delicate lab equipment, while following strict safety regulations.
- Kept a thorough record of experimental data.

Volunteer Accounting Assistant

Feb 2017 - Feb 2018

Altview | Edmonton, AB

- Book-keeping for meetings, expenditures, and initiatives.
- Working without direct supervision, while remaining a part of an integrated team.